Scott Schroeder

snschroeder89@gmail.com (281) 796-9760 Erie, CO Full Stack Developer
GitHub

<u>LinkedIn</u> Portfolio

Summary

I am a Full Stack Developer with extensive experience in Javascript/Typescript, React, Node.js, and PostgreSQL. I have built applications that handle thousands of requests a minute, connecting users and technicians to valuable diagnostic and troubleshooting data. I enjoy collaborating with others, solving novel problems, and learning new technologies.

Technical Skills

Front end: Javascript, Typescript, React, Jest/Enzyme, HTML5/CSS3

Back end: Node.js, PostgreSQL, Express, Knex.js, Mocha/Chai, MongoDB, Python, Flask

Other: Shopify, AWS (EC2, RDS, S3, Amplify), Docker, Git, JWT, Chart.js, Wordpress, Ubuntu, Agile

Experience

PS Audio

Web Developer July 2020 – Sep 2023

- Managed the day-to-day operation of the company's eCommerce platform.
- Created project documentation based on stakeholder input.
- Coded, tested, and deployed applications either privately on company intranet or publicly on AWS.
- Provided continuous support and updates based on user and stakeholder feedback.
- Identified and learned new technologies to best meet the needs of company projects.
- Designed responsive front-ends to mirror mockups or wireframes.
- Major projects:
 - PS Audio Burn-in the final checkpoint for all Power Plants manufactured
 - Allows technicians to to test units under load, certifying passing units and providing detailed troubleshooting for units that fail.
 - Provides in-depth reporting, allowing the team to track trends and adjust test parameters.
 - PS Audio PowerPlay connecting users with their data
 - Aggregates data for users' Power Plants, allowing them to review power usage, temps, etc.
 - Connects the service team to in-field units, allowing remote diagnostics and troubleshooting.

Domestic Sales Manager

Oct 2014 - May 2019

- Solely managed all US dealers, growing revenue and profit year-over-year throughout my tenure.
- Acted as liaison between sales, marketing, and engineering by managing content updates, edits, and minor bug fixes on our eCommerce platform.
- Created and distributed marketing content on the company website, forum, and through email campaigns.

THINKFUL Aug 2019 – Jan 2020

Full Stack Developer Apprentice

- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on React, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Javascript, and algorithms & data structures.
- Created and deployed mobile-first apps while learning new frameworks.
- Weekly collaborations with a senior web developer to deepen my understanding of coding concepts and best practices.

Education